https://slama.dev/comeback/
https://slama.dev/comeback/
Eight Small Hydras.
Osmkrát Malá Hydra.
Lucie Vondráčková, eight.
Lucie Vondráčková, osm.
Five Satan's Boletes.
Pětkrát Hřib Satan.
Honza Nedvěd, five.
Honza Nedvěd, pět.
Thirty Steel Wools.
Třicetkrát Drátěnka.
Eva Farná, thirty.
Eva Farná, třicet.
I don't get it.
To nechápu.
Birthmark.
Robnátka.
Fifteen Bald Bores.
Patnáctkrát Plešatá Nuda.
Danda, fifteen.
Danda, patnáct.
Tomáš, how can you keep putting up with this from Ozzák?
Tomáši, jak tohle můžete Ozzákovi pořád trpět?
He keeps the sales records on this thing.
Evidenci prodeje vede na tomhle.
His documents are a mess.
Doklady má v nepořádku.
He wallpapered the storage room with the invoices from February 2004.
Fakturami za únor 2004 vytapetoval kumbál.
September 2005 blew away in the wind and don't even get me started on June 2006, because I have my dignity.
Září 2005 mu přivzal vítr a o červnu 2006 ani nemluvím, protože mám svoji důstojnost.
Calm down!
Klid!
We'll manage everything with Helenka.
S Helenkou to všechno zvládneme.
Yeah, I already told you, I've had her since... '92.
Jo, už jsem vám říkal, že já ji mám od roku... 92.
Seven times.
Sedmkrát.
The first Czech accounting program.
První český účetní program.
We've been pulling together in business since the start.
V biznisu to spolutáhneme od začátku.
And she's never betrayed me.
A nikdy mě nezradila.
Unlike our accountant.
Na rozdíl od naší účetní.
You're being unfair to her.
Jste k ní nespravedlivý.
The woman can't count.
Vždyť ta ženská neumí počítat.
Yeah, and deserting right before the tax office inspection, that's what I call outright betrayal.
Jo, a dezertovat těsně před kontrolou z berňáku, tomu já říkám vyložená zrada.
Come, come here, come on.
Pojďte, pojďte sem, pojďte.
Careful.
Pozor.
Jesus, this takes forever.
Ježíš, toto trvá.
Zoran has the Alexis 2008 program.
Zoran má program Alexis 2008.
You should see it, super fast.
To byste viděl, fofr.
It can even handle creative accounting.
Zvládá i kreativní účetnictví.
You type in whatever loss you want and it takes care of everything.
Napíšete, jakou chcete ztrátu a on už se o všechno postará.
No, no.
Ne, ne.
Better slow but proper.
Raději pomalu, ale pořádně.
Have a coffee, I'll be done in a bit.
Dejte si kávičku, za chvíli jsem hotová.
Yeah.
No.
I'll put on coffee for him.
Postavím mu do na kafe.
I'll have some when I feel like it.
Já si dám, až já budu mít chuť.
Once the inspectors get everything from Helenka nice and tidy in neat columns, they won't even think to look at the state of our paperwork.
Až to ta kontrola dostane od Helenky pěkně přehledně v úhledných sloupečcích, ani nenapadne prohlížet, v jakým stavu máme papíry.
And that's the point, because sometimes they look like someone used them to clog a toilet drain.
A to je účel, protože ty občas vypadají, jako kdyby s nima někdo ucpal odtok na záchodě.
You mean March 2006?
Myslíte březen 2006?
For God's sake.
Pro boha.
He actually did that?
On to vážně udělal?
Luckily he was just straining mortar through them.
Naštěstí si přes něj jenom cedil meltu.
Tomáš, I've found out.
Tomáši, zjistila jsem.
Still says error disk?
Pořád píše error disk?
Yeah.
Jo.
You know, Tomáš, it could be worse.
Víte, Tomáši, může být hůř.
It can't.
Nemůže.
Iva called a moment ago.
Před chvílí volala Iva.
She went with Saša to meet the Dalai Lama.
Šla se Sašou na setkání s Dalajlámou.
Lexa couldn't go because he has chicken pox.
Lexa se ale nemohl, protože má neštovice.
That's not so terrible.
To snad není taková hrůza.
The girls took Ozzák instead.
Holky místo něho vzaly Ozzáka.
Do you still think it could be worse?
Pořád si ještě myslíte, že může být hůř?
It could.
Může.
I've already found out who they're sending from the tax office.
Už jsem zjistila, koho k nám pošlou z toho berňáku.
It's Otto Schluss.
Je to Otto Schluss.
Otto Schluss?
Otto Schluss?
Bulldog Otto.
Bulldog Otto.
A few years ago he audited the electric company.
Před pár lety kontroloval ČEZ.
They had to raise electricity prices to cover the penalties.
Museli zdražit elektřinu, aby měli na penále.
Twice.
Dvakrát.
Ozzák sold some music.
Ozzák prodal muziku.
Halloween, two copies.
Halloween dvakrát.
Hi, dad.
Čau, tatí.
Peace be with you.
Mír s vámi.
Where's Ozzák?
Kde Ozzák?
Was he arrested or did he escape?
Zatkli ho nebo utekl?
Bro, don't you know I banned you from religious events ever since you told the Pope about goulash with sixers?
Brácha, ty nevíš, že jsem ti zakázal náboženský akce od té doby, co jsi řekl papeži o guláši se šesti?
He shouldn't wear the same hat as the cook at the Rotunda.
Nemá chodit ve stejný čepici jako kuchař od rotundy.
He actually didn't embarrass us today, if you don't count the nagging about schnitzels.
Náhodou dneska žádnou ostudu neudělal, když nepočítám to otravování s řízkama.
Goose schnitzels are part of every feast.
K posvícení přece patří husí řízky.
The lecture was called "The Path to Enlightenment."
Ta přednáška se jmenovala cesta k osvícení.
That's what it was.
To přece bylo.
Ground floor.
Přízemí.
The ground floor had the same squat as the balcony.
V přízemí měli stejný prd jako na balkóně.
Not even a meatball.
Ani karbanátek.
But that guy in the bedsheet spoke well.
Ale ten chlapík v tom prostěradle mluvil dobře.
Mr. Ozzák, that was His Holiness the Dalai Lama.
Pane Ozzáku, to byla jeho svatost Dalajláma.
Nonsense.
Nesmysl.
I can still tell a man from a woman, can't I?
Chlapa od ženský ještě poznám, ne?
I liked how he said we should seek the light and follow it.
Líbilo se mi, jak říkal, že máme hledat světlo a jít za ním.
And when I told him that's pretty hard because someone keeps stealing the lightbulbs in the bathroom at the Jezevec pub.
A když jsem mu říkal, že to je dost těžký, protože na hajzlíkách u Jezevce pořád někdo krade žárovky.
Good Lord.
Pane Bože.
So he patted me on the head and gave me this fat guy.
Tak mě pohladil po hlavě a dal mi tady toho tlouštíka.
He said it'll show me the way.
Prý mi ukáže cestu.
Then tell it to show you really fast.
Tak mu řekni, ať ti ukáže hodně rychle.
Come on, if we don't get this sorted soon, we're in big trouble.
Pojďme, jestli tohle brzo nedáme dohromady, tak nás čeká velkej problém.
Big trouble!
Velkej problém!
The Dalai Lama
Dalajláma
says that if a problem has a solution, there's no need to worry.
říká, že když má problém řešení, není třeba si dělat starosti.
If it doesn't, worrying won't help.
Když ho nemá, starosti nepomohou.
I'd like to see your Dalai Lama, what he'd do if his accounting for November was on soup packet wrappers and the tax office inspection is in two days.
Ale to bych ho chtěl vidět toho vašeho Dalajlámu, co by dělal, kdyby měl účetnictví za listopad na pytlíkách od gulášovky a za dva dny má kontrolu z berňáku.
Good evening.
Dobrý večer.
And if germ carriers broke into his apartment?
A kdyby mu vlezli do bytu bacilonosiči?
Hey, bro.
Čau, segráku.
Mom says you have to run to the pharmacy for me.
Máma říká, že mi máš skočit do lékárny.
I hope it won't be cod liver oil again, like when I had a broken rib.
Doufám, že to zas nebude rybí tuk, jako když jsem měl zlomený žebro.
So what?
Tak co?
Until you're healthy, don't come in here.
Dokud nebudeš zdravej, tak sem nelez.
OUT!
VEN!
The Dalai Lama says anger and hatred are like a fishhook.
Dalajláma říká, že vztek a nenávist jsou jako rybářský háček.
You need to make sure you haven't gotten caught on it.
Je třeba se ujistit, zda jsme se na něj nechytili.
My thoughts exactly.
Moje řeč.
Ozzák, if you don't stop bugging me, you'll go look for the invoices from September 2005.
Ozzáku, jestli mě nepřestaneš štvát, pomůžeš pro faktury za září 2005.
And you know what that means!
A ty víš, co to znamená!
Come on, show me the way to the Jezevec.
Pojď, ukážeš mi cestu do Jezevce.
Free Tibet.
Svobodu Tibetu.
What do you think?
Co tomu říkáte?
Iva, that suits you.
Iva, to ti sekne.
Lexa, can you even go out in public with those spots?
Lexo, můžeš s těma flekama vůbec chodit mezi lidi?
I can.
Můžu.
Shame.
Škoda.
The potassium permanganate isn't working.
Ten hypermangan nezabírá.
Potassium permanganate.
Hypermangan.
Mom says we're poor and three medicines have to be enough for everything.
Máma říká, že jsme chudí a že nám musí na všechno stačit tři léky.
Cod liver oil, potassium permanganate, and a jog around the park.
Rybí tuk, hypermangan a poklus okolo parku.
The jog is the worst, but works the best.
Ten je nejhorší, ale nejvíc funguje.
I've drunk a whole bottle of that purple gunk and still nothing.
Už jsem toho fialovýho hnusu vypil celou flašku a furt nic.
I don't get it.
Já tomu nerozumím.
So if the Tibetans are being oppressed, why don't they make a deal with some big country to protect them?
Tak když jsou Tibetáci utlačovaný, proč se nedomluví s nějakou velkou zemí, aby je chránila?
China, for example, is pretty close.
Třeba ta Čína je docela blízko.
Ozzák, it's a bit more complicated than that.
Ozzáku, je to trochu složitější.
Oh sure, they let themselves be oppressed and then look forward to the reincarnation.
No jasně, oni se nechají utlačovat a pak se těší na tu reinkarnaci.
They die, get born again and they're fine.
Umřou, znova se narodí a jsou v pohodě.
Yeah, you mean reincarnation.
Jo, ty myslíš tu reinkarnaci.
Well, I'd like to be born as something different.
No, mně by se líbilo narodit se jako něco jinýho.
Something nice that people are interested in and love.
Něco hezkýho, co lidi zajímá a mají to rádi.
Like a pony.
Třeba poník.
Well that's going to be tough, because people get reincarnated as animals as punishment for behaving badly.
No to budeš mít těžký, protože do zvířat se lidi převtělujou za trest, když se chovají hnusně.
Really?
Fakt?
I'd want to be Ozzák again in my next life.
Já bych chtěl být v příštím životě zase Ozzák.
It suits me.
Mě to vyhovuje.
But when you reincarnate, you're born in a different time and to different people.
Jenomže když se převtělíš, tak se narodíš v jiný době a jiným lidem.
Oh really?
Jo tak?
What if I was born to you?
Co kdybych se narodil tobě?
What?
Co?
No, not now, later, when you find yourself a proper man.
No ne, později, až si najdeš nějakýho pořádnýho chlapa.
Oh man.
Ty jo.
Iva, will you marry me?
Ivo, vezmeš si mě?
Lexa, don't you ever ask me that again.
Lexo, na tohle se mě už nikdy nezeptáš.
Now go and get treatment.
A teď si běž léčit.
Iva.
Ivo.
Sis, you tripped me.
Segra, ty jsi mi nastavila nohu.
Not good enough for a pony.
To na poníka nestačí.
Now we'll see.
Teď se uvidí.
Careful.
Pozor.
You saved them.
Vy jste je zachránil.
Shame.
Škoda.
Marcelka, could you go to the back for a moment?
Marcelko, mohla byste jít na chvíli dozadu?
Count how many Boney M. albums we have back there. Good as new.
Spočítat, kolik tam máme výběrů Boney M. Úplně jako nová.
And clean as the word of God.
A čistá jako slovo Boží.
So without Helenka you have to re-enter everything?
To tam jako bez Helenky musíte všechno zadávat znovu?
Wait.
Moment.
You've been entering data into it?
Vy do toho něco zadáváte?
Well of course, it has the accounting in it.
No samozřejmě, má v tom účetnictví.
Man, have you lost your mind?
Člověče, zbláznil jste se.
You don't know.
Vy to nevíte.
What?
Co?
That program was made by a complete nutcase.
Ten program dělal úplnej magor.
He was going through a divorce, was angry at the whole world, so instead of a calculator he built in a random number generator.
Rozváděl se se ženou, byl naštvaný na celý svět a tak do toho zabudoval místo kalkulátoru generátor náhodných čísel.
So...
Takže...
But I never needed a calculator.
Ale já jsem nikdy žádný kalkulátor nepotřeboval.
Helenka always calculated everything herself.
Helenka vždycky všechno spočítala sama.
Calculated, more like guessed, like playing the lottery.
Spočítala, tipovala, jako ve Sportce.
The odds of getting it right were about one in a million.
Pravděpodobnost, že se trefí, byla tak jedna ku milionu.
Only four copies were sold before they figured it out.
Prodaly se jenom čtyři kusy, než se na to přišlo.
One went to the Kladno police, one to IPB bank, and one to some Mrs. Husáčková.
Jeden měla policie Kladno, jeden IPB a jeden nějaká paní Husáčková.
And she was the only one who didn't go to jail.
A ta taky jediná nešla bručet.
Because she was the oldest citizen in the Liberec region.
Protože to byla nejstarší občanka na Liberecku.
Helenka?
Helenko?
Yeah, right, Helenka, Helenka.
Jo, ano, Helenka, Helenka.
That was actually his wife's name.
Tak se jmenovala totiž ta jeho stará.
Alright, so here we go.
Tak jo, tak tady to jede.
Nice to meet you.
Mě moc těšilo.
And I'll send you the invoice.
A fakturu já vám pošlu.
For the accounting, so you have it in order.
Kvůli účetnictví, abyste měl v pořádku.
Goodbye.
Nashledanou.
Shall we have a coffee?
Dáme si kávu?
Don't worry, Tomáš.
Nebojte, Tomáši.
Tomorrow I'll bring Alexis.
Zítra přinesu Alexis.
Maybe we'll manage somehow before that guy from the tax office arrives.
Třeba to nějak zvládnem, než dorazí ten panák z berňáku.
Schluss, Otto.
Schluss, Otto.
I believe you were just talking about me.
Myslím, že jste o mně zrovna mluvili.
You see, Mr. Schluss, we've had a rather unpleasant incident.
Víte, pane Schlussi, nám se stala taková nepříjemná věc.
You haven't by any chance lost your accounting records?
Neztratilo se vám náhodou účetnictví?
How did you guess?
Jak jste to uhodl?
A lucky guess.
Ty prstem si.
I'll check the original documents.
Zkontroluji originální doklady.
Unless they burned down, or something?
Pokud ovšem nezhořely, nebo tak něco?
And is that a big complication?
A je to velká komplikace?
Not really.
Ani ne.
But it makes me grumpy and when I'm grumpy, I tend to be thorough during inspections.
Ale jsem z toho mrzutý a když jsem mrzutý, bývám při kontrole pečlivý.
Are you making coffee?
Děláte si kávu?
I'll put the water on right away.
Já hned postavím vodu.
One-to-one Arabica with Robusta, unpasteurized milk, goat.
Jedna ku jedné arabiku s robustou, nepasterizované mléko, kozí.
You don't have any.
Vy nemáte.
Well, never mind.
No, nevadí.
And where will you seat me?
A kam mě posadíte?
By law I'm entitled to a quiet, clean environment.
Dle zákona mám nárok na tiché, čisté prostředí.
In the storage room.
V kumbále.
Here in the storage room you'll have peace and quiet, and it'll be clean too.
Tady v kumbále budete mít klid a čisto taky.
Marcelka will sweep.
Marcelka zamete.
Do we have a broom?
Máme koště?
I'll buy one.
Koupím.
This reminds me of the enriched uranium storage where they put me in Temelín.
Připomíná mi to skladiště obohaceného uranu, kam mě posadili v Temelíně.
I felt quite cramped there.
Tam jsem se cítil dost stísněně.
And when I feel cramped...
A když se cítím stísněně...
You get thorough?
Býváte pečlivý?
Yes, I get thorough.
Ano, jsem pečlivý.
Just a moment.
Moment.
I just had an idea.
Něco mě napadlo.
In case you fancy a little snack.
Kdybyste měl chuť na něco malého.
Why thank you.
Tak děkuji.
How did you know I'm on a diet?
Jak jste věděl, že držím dietu?
Oh come on now.
Ty prosím tě.
They had bigger ones in Temelín.
V Temelíně měli větší.
They grow them there themselves.
Pěstují si je tam sami.
They have a little greenhouse in the cooling tower.
Mají takové malé pařeniště v chladící věži.
They took good care of me.
Nestarali se o mě špatně.
I gained 40 kilos there.
Přibral jsem tam 40 kilo.
You can't even tell.
Ani to není vidět.
It didn't do them any good.
Nebylo jim to nic platné.
Then I arranged an audit in Františkovy Lázně.
Potom jsem si zařídil kontrolu ve Františkových Lázních.
They prepared a special program for me there.
Připravili tam pro mě speciální program.
Diet, yoga, meditation.
Dieta, jóga, meditace.
And how did that turn out?
A jak to dopadlo?
I'm thin as a reed.
Jsem jako proutek.
And how long does an audit take for a small company like mine?
A jak dlouho trvá kontrola takové malé firmy, jako je ta moje?
A day, two, a year.
Den, dva, rok.
It varies.
To je různé.
Depends on how much you find.
Podle toho, kolik se toho najde.
But when nothing is found, it goes quickly, right?
Ale když se nic nenajde, tak to jde rychle, že?
Something always turns up.
Vždycky se něco najde.
You just have to look hard enough.
Stačí pořádně hledat.
Hi, dad.
Ahoj, tati.
I'd like to...
Chtěla bych...
Ivuška, this is Mr. Schluss.
Ivuško, tohleto je pan Schluss.
He's doing our audit, so it doesn't matter what you want, because you should want it somewhere else.
Dělá nám tady kontrolu, takže je úplně jedno, co chceš, protože bys to měla chtít jinde.
But this is important.
Ale tohle je důležitý.
What is it?
Co to je?
A Tibetan flag.
Tibetská vlajka.
We have to hang it in protest against China.
Musíme ji vyvěsit na protest proti Číně.
We tried at school, but the principal told us that human rights have no place at the grammar school.
Zkoušeli jsme to ve škole, ale ředitel nám řekl, že na gymnáziu nemají lidská práva co dělat.
Well, it won't work here either.
No, tady to taky nejde.
Mr. Schluss needs peace and quiet and he couldn't care less about China.
Pan Schluss potřebuje klid a nějaká Čína je mu prostě ukradená.
Right?
Že?
Not at all.
Ale vůbec ne.
We could learn from China.
Od Číny bychom se mohli učit.
There, when you owe more than 100,000 yuan in taxes, they chop off both your hands.
Tam, když dlužíte na daních víc než 100 000 yuanů, useknou vám obě ruce.
Well, you heard him.
No, tak jste to slyšeli.
No flag and that's final.
Žádná vlajka a hotovo.
Besides, it would block Mr. Schluss's light and when something blocks Mr. Schluss's light, he gets thorough.
Stejně by tady stínila panu Schlussovi a panu Schlussovi, když něco stíní, tak bývá pečlivý.
Little girl, give me back that pen.
Holčičko, vrať mi tu tužku.
Ouch.
Au.
Oh, Saša!
No, Sašo!
Sorry, she wants to be a pony.
Promiňte, ona chce být poník.
And why is he laughing like that?
A proč se tak směje?
Because he doesn't give a damn about anything.
Protože má všechno na háku.
He reminds me of a classmate from elementary school.
Připomíná mi jednoho spolužáka ze základky.
Mirek Kláda.
Mirek Kláda.
He had dropsy.
Měl vodnatelnost.
Did he laugh too?
Taky se smál?
All the time.
Furt.
Then it could be him.
Tak to by mohl být on.
This one can simply say, in my next life I want to be Kláda.
Tenhle si totiž klidně může říct, v příštím životě chci být Kláda.
And he is Kláda.
A je Kláda.
Now that's what I call a win.
No, tomu říkám výhra.
And since when are you interested in this stuff?
A od kdy ty se vlastně zajímáš o tyhle věci?
Since I got to know those Tibetans.
Od té doby, co se znám s těma Tibeťákama.
I think reincarnation seems like a pretty good idea.
Mně ta reinkarnace přijde jako docela dobrý nápad.
You die, get born again, wait eleven, twelve years and you can drink again.
Umřeš, znovu se narodíš, počkáš jedenáct, dvanáct let a můžeš zas chlastat.
Hey.
Čau.
Auntie, could I hang this up here?
Teto, mohla bych to tady vyvěsit?
No football, I don't want my regulars fighting in here.
Žádnej fotbal, ještě se mi tady servou štamgasti.
It's not a party flag.
To není vlajka od partaje.
And what regulars?
A jaký štamgasti?
Ozzák would have to fight with himself here.
Vždyť by se tady Ozzák musel servat sám se sebou.
That's happened before.
To už tady taky byl.
Alright, hang it up there, at least it'll cover up that scribble.
No tak dobře, tak to pověs tam, ale aspoň nebude vidět ta čmáranice.
Whoa, who did that?
Tyjo, kdo to udělal?
Saša.
Saša.
She surprised me, that girl.
Překvapila mě, holka.
Did she run out of chalk?
To jí došla křída?
More like courage.
Spíš odvaha.
She threw the chalk down, shrieked something, and ran away.
Křídu zahodila, něco zaříchtala a utekla.
Hey, Ivona, leave it.
Hele, Ivono, nech to tak.
What kind of mom would I be if I didn't keep my children's drawings?
No co bych to byla za mámu, kdybych si nenechávala obrázky svých dětí?
Bye.
Čau.
Mom, I still think it's not working.
Mami, já si myslím, že to furt nezabírá.
So what are you waiting for?
No tak na co čekáš?
To the park, go.
Do parku, ne.
At least three laps.
Aspoň tři kolečka.
April 2005.
Duben 2005.
I'm used to a lot, but...
Jsem zvyklý na ledacos, ale...
February accounting on election flyers, March on coffee filters, and April on envelope liners?
Únorové účetnictví na volebních letácích, březnové na kávových filtrech a dubnové na futrech?
I've never seen that before.
To jsem ještě nezažil.
You see, my brother has his own strong views on keeping accounting records.
Víte, on můj bratr má k vedení účetnictví svůj rázný postoj.
Very original.
Velmi originální.
The only thing he hasn't used yet is toilet paper.
Jediné, co dosud nepoužil, je toaletní papír.
Well then you shouldn't audit June 2006.
No tak to byste neměl kontrolovat červen 2006.
That's not past the statute of limitations.
To je nepromlčený.
We're missing September 2005.
Schází nám září 2005.
You see, Mr. Schluss...
Víte, pane Schlussi...
That September sort of blew away on us.
Ono to září nám tak trochu uletělo.
April on envelope liners and September blew away.
Duben na futrech a září nám uletělo.
You have one day to get those records together.
Máte den na to, abyste ty podklady sehnal.
And do you think we could somehow manage without that September?
A myslíte, že bychom se bez toho září nějak neobešli?
I doubt it.
Pochybuji.
That would be expensive.
To by bylo drahý.
Got any matches?
Máte sirky?
You think it's time to cover your tracks?
Myslíte si, že je čas zahladit stopy?
Death is just a gateway to a new life, but people are afraid to walk through it.
Smrt je jenom brána do nového života, ale lidi se jí bojí projít.
Hm?
Hm?
That was nicely said.
To jsi řekl hezky.
Then it's not Kláda.
Tak to nebude Kláda.
He was just grunting.
To je jenom chrochtal.
I wonder what it's like being dead.
Mě by zajímalo, jaký to je být mrtvej.
Why do you keep going on about death?
Proč furt meleš o smrti?
I did something bad and I think I totally wrecked my karma.
Provedl jsem něco špatnýho a asi jsem si úplně zkazil karmu.
Karma.
Karmu.
I lost some invoices for my brother and now I'm scared I'll be in trouble with him because of it.
Ztratil jsem bráchovi nějaký faktury a teď mám strach, abych kvůli tomu u něj neměl nějakej malér.
Like I might get born somewhere else, you know?
Abych se třeba nenarodil někde jinde, víš?
Or as something gross.
Nebo jako něco hnusnýho.
Like DJ Bobo.
Třeba jako DJ Bobo.
I thought I'd never say this to you of all people, but stop drinking for today.
Myslela jsem si, že zrovna tobě tohle nikdy neřeknu, ale pro dnešek už nepij.
Today is fading, tomorrow may never come, so what certainty is there in life?
Dnešek se rozplývá, zítřek přijít nemusí, jaká je tedy v životě jistota?
An installment plan.
Splátkový kalendář.
Right.
No.
What's that flag doing in the window?
Co dělá ve výloze ta vlajka?
It's a symbol that our shop stands on the side of good.
Je to symbol, že náš obchod stojí na straně dobra.
Take it down immediately.
Okamžitě ji sundáš.
Why?
Proč?
What if some Chinese person came to shop here?
Co kdyby nám přišel nakupovat nějaký Číňan?
Dad, the Chinese don't shop, the Chinese copy.
Tati, Číňani nenakupujou, Číňani kopírujou.
Then get yourself a lapel pin, protest as a private citizen and don't drag our business into economic isolation.
Tak si pořiď do klopy odznáček, protestuj si jako soukromá osoba a nezatahuj naši firmu do ekonomické izolace.
Dad, that auditor is still here.
Tati, ještě je u nás ten kontrolor.
Yes, but don't disturb him now.
Ano, ale teď ho neruš.
He's relaxing.
Relaxuje.
Has he already had his hands on March 2006?
A už měl v rukou březen 2006?
Why?
Proč?
Well, it's just that he probably wouldn't be happy to find out those weren't coffee filters.
No já jenom, že by asi nebyl rád, kdyby se dozvěděl, že to nebyly filtry od kafe.
Fine.
Dobře.
Three days the flag can stay, then you buy yourself a pin.
Tři dny tu vlajka může zůstat, pak si koupíš odznáček.
Thanks, dad.
Díky, tati.
Anti-diarrhea pills.
Prosiprotisráčková.
Children, Tomáš, you know, the rebellious phase.
Děti, Tomáši, to víte, období vzdoru.
Fine, but why is this rebellion aimed at me.
Dobře, ale proč ten vzdor jde zrovna proti mně.
Marcelka, Schluss wants September 2005.
Marcelko, Schluss chce září 2005.
Jesus, well, I don't know.
Ježíš, no to, to nevím.
Could I bring some invoices from Zoran?
Mohla bych přinést nějaké faktury od Zorana?
I think tanks, land mines and quickite won't pass Schluss's inspection.
Já myslím, že tanky, šlapné miny a nehašené vápno nám Schluss neuzná.
My husband is a businessman, not a mobster.
Můj manžel je obchodník, ne mafián.
But you said he fired a bazooka on New Year's Eve.
Vždyť jste říkala, že na Silvestra střílel z bazuky.
Anyway, Schluss said it's going to be expensive without that September.
No nic, Schluss říkal, že bez toho září to bude drahý.
I'm not going to send my own brother to his death over the tax office.
Já přece nepošlu vlastního bratra na smrt kvůli berňáku.
Mirek Kláda?
Mirek Kláda?
So you came from there?
Takže ty jsi přišel odtamtud?
For the audit.
Na kontrolu.
I wouldn't have expected you here.
Tady bych tě teda nečekal.
Nobody does.
To nikdo.
Still got that sense of humor.
V tobě ten vtip.
Hey, do you remember anything from before you came here?
Ty, pamatuješ si něco z toho, než jsi přišel sem?
What was it like there?
Jaký to tam bylo?
Cramped.
Stísněné.
And enlightenment, did you experience it?
A osvícení, zažil jsi?
Fortunately not.
Naštěstí ne.
I had a dosimeter.
Měl jsem dozimetr.
A dosimeter?
Dozimetr?
So they have dosimeters there?
Tak u něj existují dozimetry?
They're mandatory there.
Tam jsou povinný.
I know why you came.
Já vím, proč jsi přišel.
Because of those invoices, right?
Kvůli těm fakturám, viď?
That too.
To taky.
So if I bring that September, we'll be cool?
Takže když to září donesu, budeme spolu v pohodě?
Definitely more than now.
Rozhodně víc než teď.
Thanks.
Dík.
You're a legend.
Jseš frajer.
You know, Mr. Schluss...
Víte, pane Schlussi...
Yes?
Prosím?
Spending time together like this...
Když tak spolu trávíme čas...
I've realized how easily friendship between men can develop.
Uvědomil jsem si, jak vlastně snadno může vzniknout mezi muži přátelství.
You think so?
Myslíte?
Well yes, that's why I'd very much like to give you this little something.
No ano, proto bych vám velice rád věnoval tuhle maličkost.
Well, so you'll remember me fondly...
No, abyste na mě vzpomínal v dobrém...
I'm the one who wrote the introduction.
To jsem já uvedl.
South Bohemia in Photography.
Jižní Čechy ve fotografii.
You might like the photograph on page 246.
Možná by se vám mohla líbit fotografie na straně 246.
Boubín.
Boubín.
I don't like it.
Nelíbí.
No, 346, I made a mistake, 346.
Ne, 346, spletl jsem se, 346.
Look, Mr. Pacovský, when I convert this to a percentage of income, you're offering me more than the guys from the electric company, but let's each stay on our own side of the barricade.
A podívejte se, pane Pacovský, když to přepočtu na procenta z příjmu, nabízíte mi víc než ti hoši od elektřiny, ale zůstáváme raději každý na své straně barikády.
So we can't do without September 2005.
Takže bez září 2005 se neobejdeme.
Do you even realize what an inhuman system you're part of?
A uvědomujete si vůbec, jak je to nelidský systém, kterého jste součástí?
A system that forces a person to choose between debtors' prison and frying his own brother?
Který nutí člověka, aby se musel rozhodnout mezi vězením pro dlužníky a usmažením vlastního bratra?
Bro, I've got September 2005.
Brácha, nesu září 2005.
That fat guy showed me the way.
Ten tlouštík mi ukázal cestu.
Well you see, you just have to look hard enough.
No vidíte, stačí pořádně hledat.
So to sum it up, something always turns up.
Tak abychom to shrnuli, vždycky se něco najde.
However, compared to Temelín, it wasn't exactly a big explosion.
Ovšem, když to srovnám s Temelínem, tak velkej výbuch to zase nebyl.
But I had to reassess your tax for the years 2003, 2005 and 2006.
Ale musel jsem vám doměřit daň za roky 2003, 2005 a 2006.
Such errors in the totals, I've never seen the likes.
Tedy takové chyby v součtech, to jsem ještě neviděl.
Nevertheless, the total comes to 120,378 crowns.
Nicméně, celkem to dělá 120 378 korun.
But...
Ale...
However, for the years 2004 and 2007 you have such absurd overpayments for the same reason that we'll actually be returning 8 crowns to you.
Ovšem, za roky 2004 a 2007 máte ze stejného důvodu tak absurdní přeplatky, že vám budeme ještě 8 korun vracet.
You can request them by registered mail.
Můžete si o ně požádat doporučeným dopisem.
Well, take care.
Tak se tu mějte.
I've got the Czech Gas Company next.
Mě čeká Česká plynárenská.
Goodbye.
Nashledanou.
I haven't heard that in a long time.
To už jsem dlouho neslyšel.
Someone should have a talk with Saša.
S tou Sašou by měl někdo promluvit.
Yeah.
Jo.
Helenka.
Helenku.
You came out better than one acquaintance of mine.
Dopadl jste líp než jeden z mých známých.
I didn't want to tell you.
Nechtěla jsem vám to říkat.
But when he found out Schluss was coming for an audit, he set fire to his asbestos mine.
Ale když zjistil, že k němu jde Schluss na kontrolu, podpálil svůj azbestový důl.
He even caught him putting the gasoline in his expenses.
Přišel mu i na to, že si dal ten benzín do nákladů.
Tomáš, I have a gift for you.
Tomáši, mám pro vás dárek.
Please.
Prosím.
Alexis 2008.
Alexis 2008.
Recommended by the Icelandic Ministry of Finance and Viktor Kožený.
Doporučuje islandské ministerstvo financí a Viktor Kožený.
Good day.
Dobrý den.
Hi, mom.
Čau, mami.
I see the spots are gone.
Koukám, fleky pryč.
Nothing like a good run in the park, right?
Není nad to se pořádně proběhnout v parku, viď?
Actually, I went to the doctor.
Já jsem byl ale u doktora.
The teacher sent me there because she couldn't stand looking at my spotty face anymore.
Třídní mě tam poslala, že už se na ten můj kropenatej ksicht nemůže dívat.
Well, I'll have to have a word with her.
No, asi si s ním budu muset promluvit.
I decide when my kids are sick, got it?
Já rozhoduju o tom, kdy jsou moje děcka nemocný, jasný?
You're not even going to ask me what the doctor said?
A to se mě ani nezeptáš, co mi ten doktor řek?
Well?
No.
The first spots were apparently just regular rashes and the rest were an allergy to the potassium permanganate.
Ty první fleky prej byly obyčejný neděry a ty další alergie na hypermangan.
There were always problems with you.
S tebou byly vždycky problémy.
Want to hear that at least Sašenka got better?
Chceš říct, že se aspoň ta Sašenka zpravila?
His Holiness is looking for spiritual music.
Jeho svatost se shání po duchovní hudbě.
Your wish shall be granted.
Tvé přání se splní.
You shall become a pony of Velhase.
Staneš se poníkem Velhase.
Yeah!
Jo!
Does the young lady know that a pony of Velhase must carry at least twice its own weight?
Ví ta mladá dáma, že poník Velhase musí unést minimálně dvojnásobek své vlastní váhy?